Finding Aid for James C. Wood pamphlets and reprints, 1890-1947
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
James C. Wood pamphlets and reprints 1890-1947
Wood, James C. (James Craven), b. 1858.
42 items (in 1 box)
[7214] DA 2; W876; P186
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The provenance of the items in this collection is uncertain.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
James C. Wood was a professor of obstetrics and diseases of women and children at the University of Michigan Homeopathic Medical College.
This collection of pamphlets and reprints of the writings of James C. Wood was gathered together from different sources. The collection is arranged alphabetically by title.
- Pamphlets and reprints
  - The American college of surgeons and fee-splitting, 1914 (Box 1)
  - Carcinoma of the uterus, 1896 (Box 1)
  - A case of heart massage through the diaphragm after apparent death-recovery, 1914 (Box 1)
  - Celiotomy during pregnancy--six clinical cases, 1906 (Box 1)
  - Cervical tears, 1920 (Box 1)
  - A clinical case with comments, 1904 (Box 1)
  - The creation of a new vagina, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Cystic distension of the appendix vermiformis, with the review of the literature of the subject, 1900 (Box 1)
  - The determination of sex, 1918 (Box 1)
  - Diagnosis, differential diagnosis, and pathology of cystitis and urethritis in women, 1900 (Box 1)
  - Ectopic pregnancy following ligature and section of fallopian tubes, 1917 (Box 1)
  - Epilepsy as a histero-neurosis, 1891. Gynecological clinic, University of Michigan Homeopathic department, Session of 1890-1891, 1891 (Box 1)
  - How can the teaching of the specialities in the undergraduate course be made to serve its true and best purpose-the qualification of the student for general practice, 1898 (Box 1)
  - An ideal summer outing, 1907 (Box 1)
  - In memoriam. Adolph Benedict Schneider, M.D., 1947 (Box 1)
  - Is there a scientific concept of homeopathy? 1931 (Box 1)
  - Keloids following laparotomy, 1937 (Box 1)
  - The lady or the dog, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Man and his physician, 1928 (Box 1)
  - The medical and surgical treatment of peritonitis, 1899 (Box 1)
  - Neurasthenia of long standing, the result of numerous lesions with the pelvis-abdomen operation--recovery after prolonged convalescence, 1906 (Box 1)
  - A new operation for cystocele, 1905 (Box 1)
  - Obstruction of the bowel due to abnormal contents, 1905 (Box 1)
  - The other side of the question, undated (Box 1)
  - Philosophical thoughts on medicine, 1937 (Box 1)
  - The practical application of organotherapy, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Profound lesions within the pelvis resulting from gonorrhea giving rise to distressing indigestion, mal-nutrition, etc., undated (Box 1)
  - The proposed amalgamation of the homeopathic and regular departments of the University of Michigan: A protest (Box 1)
  - Pudendal haematocele, 1904 (Box 1)
  - The reincarnation of Richard Warrington, undated (Box 1)
  - The relations of homeopathy to allied systems of therapeutics, 1899 (Box 1)
  - Rhinophyma, 1911 (Box 1)
  - Sterility in women, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Then and now, 1825-1925. A medical drama in two acts, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Three cases of acute intestinal obstruction, 1891 (Box 1)
  - Toxicology and homeopathy, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Two cases of appendicitis associated with retroflexion of the uterus and displacement of the ovaries, 1906 (Box 1)
  - Uncorrected factors perpetuating stomach symptoms after surgical work, 1919 (Box 1)
  - University ideals in medicine, undated (Box 1)
  - The use of the spray in the local treatment of gynecological diseases, 1901 (Box 1)
  - "Whither homeopathy?" 1929 (Box 1)
  - A year's surgical work, 1902 (Box 1)